<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website of Nikhil Damodaran</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Website of Nikhil Damodaran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/about/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Assistant Professor&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jsgp.edu.in/&#34;&gt;School of Government and Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jgu.edu.in/&#34;&gt;OP Jindal Global University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cabin 6, T4, Academic Block&lt;br /&gt;
OP Jindal Global University, Sonipat, Haryana&lt;br /&gt;
Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ndamodaran@jgu.edu.in&#34;&gt;ndamodaran@jgu.edu.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research focuses on transmission of economic policy across open economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I examine transmission in a variety of setting. I analyze regional economies which form a part of a fiscal unions in my paper “Fiscal Policy and Transmission: The Case of India’s States”, which is currently under review. I also look at transmission of fiscal policies for the Eurozone in my paper “Trade Transmission of Fiscal Policies in a Currency Union”. I am broadly interested in the effect of policy transmission for these regions especially due to their huge interdependence, which makes policy making a strategic and consequnetial exercise for these regions - in addition to its contributions to supra-regional economic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In similar spirit, I examine transmission of Demonetization shock on the Indian economy in a paper “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.monash.edu/__data/assets/pdf_file/0005/2252795/07-20-Consumer-payment-choice-and-demonetizationedited-final.pdf&#34;&gt;Consumer Payment Choice and the Heterogeneous Impact of India’s Demonetization&lt;/a&gt;” in which we look at the disaggregate effects of India’s demonetization through short payment choices for consumers. This is largely regional transmission of this monetary shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teaching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I teach Macroeconomics I and &lt;a href=&#34;post/macro/&#34;&gt;II&lt;/a&gt;, International Trade, &lt;a href=&#34;post/maths/&#34;&gt;Mathematical Methods for Economics&lt;/a&gt;, Statistics II all of which are compulsary courses for BA.(Hons) Economics at O.P. Jindal Global University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Methods for Economics</title>
      <link>/post/maths/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/maths/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mathematics is central to undergraduate economics. The key is to learn only as much as is required for you to use economics in daily life. For my undergraduate class, I teach students to be street smart in mathematics and learn the maths which helps them get through undergraduate economics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding IS-LM Models</title>
      <link>/post/analytics-is-lm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analytics-is-lm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction After a preview of AD-AS we move onto a bit more detailed model using IS-LM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Business Cycles from Time Series Data</title>
      <link>/post/extracting-business-cycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/extracting-business-cycles/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started We start with the basics of R, exploring the memory and clearing out backlog from previous work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomics II</title>
      <link>/post/macro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/macro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lectures notes from my course on macroeconomics at the OP Jindal Global University&amp;rsquo;s School of Government and Public Policy. Check out the latest debate about India&amp;rsquo;s macroeconomic policy in my lecture notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Value Chain</title>
      <link>/post/breaking-the-value-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/breaking-the-value-chain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s CoVID-19 response has been making headlines around the globe.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; These are not related to lapses in public health system or inaction against the then impending pandemic. Instead the attention is on its administrative inability to plan the lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started-with-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R is a statistical computing platform designed to make data analysis open and scientific. &amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo; is for anyone to access understand and replicate. The functionalities of R are open so much so that you can even make your own version of R - though you would be wasting a lot of time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks</title>
      <link>/post/bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A collection of my frequently visited websites for news, views and economics.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certified Copy</title>
      <link>/post/certified-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/certified-copy/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Will you be interested in a work of art if you knew it is a replica or will you show sanctity to the ‘original’?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I completed my Ph.D. from the Department of Agricultural Economics at the Louisiana State University back in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Working Paper Fiscal Policy and Transmission: The Case of India&amp;rsquo;s States Abstract: The magnitude of interstate trade in India adds a unique dimension to within and interstate transmission of fiscal policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>My lecture notes are available in the blue hyperlinks , whenever highlighted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>